World War II.
For the first time in the world,
a country used a nuclear bomb.
Though American atomic bombings
on Hiroshima and Nagasaki
put an end to the World War,
it started a new kind of race
in the world.
A race to build nuclear bombs.
The ultimate symbol of power.
1971. Pakistan lost the war
to India for the third time.
They wanted revenge at all costs.
They had only one way left
to defeat India.
To make a nuclear bomb.
However, wars are not won with weapons,
but with intelligence.
And India's trump card was RAW.
Our RAW agents infiltrated Pakistan
from Peshawar to Karachi.
They were not tasked to use firearms,
but to find critical information
and send it to Delhi.
Away from their land,
they were the soldiers of the land.
My name is R.N. Kao. I'm the chief of RAW.
And this is the story
of one such gallant soldier.
God is great
I bear witness
That there is no god except the One God
Hey, Anwar!
- Tariq.
- Peace be upon you.
- How are you?
- All well by God's grace, Anwar.
Did you talk to your uncle about me?
I did, but he doesn't need
new workers right now.
If you could arrange a meeting, Anwar.
You won't find a better tailor
than me in all of Pakistan.
We've been doing it
for generations. It's in my blood.
But they don't have an opening.
I hear the army is recruiting people.
Your uncle must be swamped
with orders to sew new uniforms.
Try to understand, Anwar.
I don't want to be stuck
sewing women's clothing forever.
And they drive a hard bargain.
- What can a 2-meter fabric...
- Help him out, Anwar.
He's a God-fearing man.
He prays five times a day.
I'm trying, Maulvi Saab.
- Tell your uncle I recommended him.
- Sure.
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
Thank you so much, Maulvi Saab.
- May God protect you.
Army uniforms
are not like women's clothing.
MOMIN TAILORS
- Do you know how to cut sleeves?
- Yes.
Let me see.
Here.
Thread a needle.
Come on, sir.
I can do it even while I'm sneezing.
Do it.
You better sneeze, boy.
Maybe that'll help.
He needs training.
I'll pay you 300 rupees a month.
Does that work for you?
Who will work for that?
Right, Tariq? Is that okay?
- Works for me.
- He agreed!
You start tomorrow, son.
Be careful! Are you crazy?
- I told you so many times!
- Dad.
- Come on! Get in the car.
- The girl made you lose your mind.
You agreed to work for 300 rupees.
Good.
Nasreen, Uncle Momin's niece.
Poor girl is blind from birth.
Nasreen.
My Lord knows
How I love you
Yeah, my Lord knows
My Lord knows
How I love you
My heart longs for you
I've lost my heart to you
All I wish for is you
Yeah, my Lord knows
My Lord knows
How I love you
Oh, those beautiful eyes
Have stolen my heart
My world is in your eyes
Oh, those beautiful eyes
Have stolen my heart
My world is in your eyes
Why don't you drop me?
You're not as stealthy as you think.
I recognize your perfume
from the first day.
Come, let's get going.
It will be dark soon.
I am used to the dark.
Are you afraid of it?
How one falls in love
How the world turns colorful
I see it in your eyes
What the moonlight is
How the lamps light up
I see it in your eyes
Oh, I wonder how the day rushes by
I'm lost in my thoughts
All I wish for is you
My Lord knows
How I love you
How I love you...
How dare you?
You'll regret it
if I see you anywhere near her.
- Listen to me.
- He has ill intentions.
How would you feel
if he had eyes for your daughter?
I'm holding back because you are
Nasreen's father, or else...
This is his true self. He's a goon.
I love Nasreen.
I want to marry her.
He is a good, honest man,
where will we find anyone better?
So I should hand my daughter
to an illiterate man?
- How will he keep her happy?
- Well, I'm sorry.
But you aren't very educated yourself.
Didn't I let you marry my sister?
If her mom were alive,
she would have talked some sense into her.
Dad, you know,
I don't mind that I'm blind.
But after Mom passed away,
I was a burden to you.
Tariq gave wings to my confined life.
I breathe freely when I'm with him.
No one can love me more than Tariq.
Not even you, Dad.
You see the world with my eyes
I do.
I put you on my eyelashes
My Lord knows
How I love you
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four...
...three, two, one...
Mr. Alam, please come.
I'll read your report tomorrow.
It's my wife's birthday today.
It's not a report, sir.
It's news from India.
We would like to tell our audience
that India has successfully carried out
its first nuclear bomb test explosion.
This operation was codenamed
Smiling Buddha.
And it was carried out
in Pokhran, Rajasthan
under the supervision
of the Indian Army and scientists.
Hello.
- Can you hear me?
- Hello.
Yes, please speak.
I am listening to you.
Sir, what about this cake?
Sir, India has declared it
a peaceful nuclear test.
Peaceful nuclear test, my foot!
Consider it a threat from India.
We've already lost East Pakistan.
Now, we'll lose Kashmir as well.
We must accelerate
our nuclear weapon's program, sir.
That's what I wanted to hear.
Sir, we need a nuclear physicist
and metallurgical engineer for it.
And I think there's only one guy
who can do it.
A.Q. Khan. Abdul Qadeer Khan.
What do you say, Mr. Alam?
We can't trust him, sir.
Even while he was in Pakistan,
he has broken many laws.
Sir, he's doing
groundbreaking work in Holland.
He just wants results,
and he will do anything for it.
Then he's our man. Exactly who we need.
We need him back in Pakistan.
We must keep this mission
a secret from the world.
For Pakistan.
We will starve, eat grass,
but Pakistan will build a nuclear bomb!
Pakistan was ready to go to any extent
to make a nuclear bomb.
And to make it happen,
they brought in A.Q. Khan.
The most dangerous scientist in the world.
- Welcome home, sir.
- Welcome home.
- How was your journey?
- Good.
He was now
Pakistan's most important asset.
And Pakistan left no stone unturned
to keep his family happy.
Welcome home, Mr. Khan.
It's time to put India in its place.
Hidden from the world,
a location was chosen
for the nuclear facility.
Project 706, Pakistan's top secret.
The international community
must come together
to condemn India's irresponsible actions.
On one hand,
PM Bhutto was pointing fingers at India.
On the other, his illegal
nuclear program was in full swing.
Enter Colonel Gadhafi of Libya.
He's a terrorist to the world,
but for Pakistan, he's a close ally.
Gadhafi provided 500 million dollars
in funding to Pakistan.
Banned nuclear components were smuggled in
from the European black market.
And the uranium used in the nuclear bomb
was smuggled in from Africa.
Pakistan was very close
to achieving its goal.
I request the international community
to put sanctions against India.
To stop its heinous designs.
This is the main centrifuge area.
- The outer perimeter.
- And the inner perimeter?
- No, I mean...
- Now for some special news.
Today in United Nations, Pakistan has got
an important victory against India.
Declaring the Pokhran
explosions irresponsible,
India's atomic program
has been put on hold.
You burned it, didn't you?
Yikes.
That's what happens
when you cook on high heat.
- Okay.
- Move.
I'll be jinxed
if you keep staring like this.
It's my right
to look at you to my heart's content,
for I'm your husband, love of my life.
Bravo, my Shakespeare!
- Bravo.
- Thank you.
That's enough now.
The doctor advised you to rest.
There are five months to go.
I can't rest so long.
All right, then.
Are you leaving early today?
Yeah, Uncle is coming in late today.
So I have to open the shop.
Well, won't you kiss him goodbye today?
Traitor, come out!
After all...
- Traitor, come out!
- Break the door.
What's the matter?
Are you worried about the baby again?
No. I'm just a bit anxious.
- It's a huge responsibility.
- Lord Almighty has blessed us.
Trust me. You'll be the best dad.
Sir!
I don't care if I live or die.
But as long as I'm alive,
I'll continue to serve.
I'll serve this nation and its people.
Mr. Kao is here. Look.
- Who should be our PM?
- Mother of our nation!
RAW Chief is here from Delhi.
It must be a national emergency.
Madam, it is a national emergency.
Pakistan is making a nuclear bomb.
We have intel from Europe
that Pakistan bought banned
nuclear components from the black market
and imported uranium from Africa.
They stopped us
and are making one themselves?
We did everything legally.
Madam, we need to expose Pakistan.
The world needs to know the truth.
Where is their nuclear facility?
It's Pakistan's top secret.
No one knows about it.
It's a radical country.
Before launching
a nuclear attack on India...
You know they won't think twice.
I absolutely agree.
Pakistan is very close
to conducting nuclear tests.
And we must find their nuclear facility
and neutralize it before that.
What if it starts a war?
Wars only scare
those who have never won one.
Pakistan should worry about it, not us.
We are running out of time, Madam.
And we don't need ammunition here.
We need intelligence.
Someone who can pull this off
without attracting any attention.
And you have
someone like that in Pakistan?
I have just the right man for the job.
I trust you, Kao. Give him the mission.
India is counting on him.
After declaring an emergency,
election campaigns
are in full swing in India.
Because of sensitive relations
with New Delhi...
Dear, switch off the radio.
They keep yapping
about India and Pakistan all day.
- Yeah.
- Here, Tariq. Have some.
The food is delicious.
Dad, have some.
- No.
- Here.
One shouldn't act greedy
while visiting someone else's house.
Someone else's house?
You are the eldest in this family.
Please have some.
So, Tariq, have you started
looking for a better job?
Or do you plan to keep my daughter
stuck in that shack forever?
Dad, it's my house too.
I won't listen to this anymore.
Come on, brother.
- It was better with the radio on.
- India's increasing...
Nasreen.
I have to visit Naved
after dropping you home.
He got a new order from Dubai.
I'm thinking
of starting a business with him.
Since when did Dad's jabs
start bothering you?
Sometimes I feel he's right.
You could have found
someone better than me.
Well, that's true.
I just married you
because of this scooter.
If I wanted to,
I could have even married Dharmendra.
Why do girls love that actor so much?
And you haven't even seen him.
I haven't seen you either.
But that voice is all that he needs.
"I'll kill each one of you!"
- "Gabbar Singh, here I come!"
Tariq.
So, Mr. Romeo,
have you tucked the blind girl in bed?
Are you angry?
Look, Romeo, she's just a cover.
She's not your real wife.
Yes, sir.
And I hear you've started praying
five times a day.
Your traitor father
must be dancing in his grave.
Shall we get to the point, sir?
Well, I think you are useless.
But unfortunately, the boss trusts you.
Do you hear me?
Yes, sir.
I guess you know
about our fireworks in Pokhran.
Yes, sir.
Our neighbors also want to do it.
They say,
"Our fireworks will make your jaw drop."
We asked them
where they are getting those from,
where they plan to make them,
but they won't tell us.
- You must find that location.
- Okay, sir.
And this operation will be called
Mission Majnu.
Okay, sir.
There's a roadside
food stall at Chakri Road.
Go there and tell them
that you want Gorilla brand spices.
Okay, sir.
And now... say your real name.
- That's not the protocol, sir.
- Name!
- Amandeep Singh.
- Full name.
Come on, come out, traitor. Come out!
Surrender now!
- Break the door!
- Traitor!
Amandeep Ajitpal Singh.
Bloody son of a traitor.
Just rot there!
To find Pakistan's nuclear facility,
we need our best man.
We can't screw this up.
Speak frankly, Mishra.
I chose you because you have no filter.
So, tell me.
Sir, Amandeep is a mistake.
You're making a blunder
by giving him this mission.
The whole department is against it.
It was his father who had sold sensitive
military information to Pakistan.
Then how can Amandeep be reliable, sir?
His father betrayed the country
and the son is paying penance.
What could be a better reason?
If it were anyone else,
they would have changed their name
and lived an easy life.
But Aman took the tough path.
Amandeep is the number one cadet
in the history of the academy.
My best student!
He won't let India down.
But what is his reference point?
Where will he start?
Pakistan Army's headquarters
are in Rawalpindi.
And Aman knows that Pakistan
is not run by the government,
but by its army.
Hey, man! One tandoori please.
With Gorilla brand spices.
Darling, do you plan
to stay here till we get married?
Hey!
This gun is for you.
Sharma asked me to hand it to you.
And you turn me into minced meat.
Angry young man.
I want an account of every single penny.
I'm a spy, not an accountant.
Oh, my God.
A lover!
So she's your wife.
I hope you haven't fallen in love.
They teach us in training.
Whatever you do, be thorough with it.
Maybe you were sleeping in class.
How did you know? I really used to sleep.
But don't take me for a fool.
I'm a badass.
To fool around is one thing,
but marriage... Never.
I've seen many like you.
A man can turn soft.
Take the gun!
You keep it.
That's not how I work.
Of course. You work
with your killer eyes, Mr. Romeo.
At least ask my name.
- Tell me.
- Aslam Usmaniya.
That's my real name. My food is real too.
Maybe bring your wife along some day.
Come and see me if you wish
Or go to hell, darling
Sir, he's quite something.
Fit and tall with personality.
He's a man of few words.
And he's tough too.
Should I get your sister married to him?
Sir, all I mean is he's quite a guy.
Keep an eye on him.
And don't cozy up too much.
If he messes up,
you'll be the one to shoot him.
Got it?
I had to lock it. The bill got expensive.
They make calls behind my back.
And here are the keys
in case you need to make a call.
Yeah. Thank you.
- Shall I deliver the uniform?
- Yeah.
The one on top is for the brigadier.
Deliver that first.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- I'll do it.
- Okay.
Shut down your shop,
if you can't do your job well!
Sorry, sir. I'll send someone right away.
Yeah, sure.
- Rasheed!
- Yeah.
Hurry to the brigadier's place.
- What's the matter, Uncle?
- They're all useless.
Two buttons are missing
from the brigadier's uniform.
Well, don't worry.
Give me the buttons.
I'll go and fix it right away.
- And I'll apologize too.
- Yes.
That's better. He'll be glad to see
someone from the family.
- Okay.
- Here.
- Take these buttons.
- Okay.
- You are here to see the brigadier?
- Yes, sir.
Go on.
Sir, your tea.
Would you like some tea?
No, sir, I just realized.
You attended my wedding.
Right.
- Aren't you Rasool's son-in-law?
- Yes.
That's why you looked familiar.
All well with you?
Yes, by God's grace.
I'll be a dad soon, sir.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I've decided already.
If it's a boy, he'll join the army, sir.
Good.
If I were in the army,
you would have seen me
shoot each one of those Indians.
But I would've spared Hema Malini.
Sir, I read in the newspaper
that the Indians are making
a bomb called "Atom"
that can destroy all of Pakistan.
Look, if anything happens to my family,
I won't spare them, sir.
They don't practice what they preach.
They can even fix a cricket match.
That won't happen.
- Pakistan is not less than India.
- But we don't have an atom bomb, sir.
Well, we'll have one.
But how? We don't have
the money nor qualified people.
I won't make my son a soldier.
I'll make him an atom bomb expert, sir.
My son will make
an atom bomb for Pakistan.
We don't have to wait that long.
Pakistani scientists
are educated and intelligent.
They are here from abroad.
God willing, we'll get the good news soon.
Sir, are we making a bomb?
Victory to us!
Victory to Pakistan! Victory to us...
But where are they making it?
In Rawalpindi?
Because I want to see it, sir.
Well, it's around here.
Everyone will see it.
Eid celebrations will be grand this time.
Sir, it's not confirmed yet,
but there'll be fireworks before Eid.
It could very well be tomorrow.
Just give me the location.
It's not confirmed yet,
but the probability is high
it'll be around Rawalpindi.
Your assumptions are useless to me.
That's why I said, sir,
it's not confirmed yet.
I need more time and...
So when will you confirm?
After they destroy Delhi?
Protocol, sir!
To hell with your protocol.
My line is secure.
And I don't care about you.
We don't have to wait that long.
Pakistani scientists
are educated and intelligent.
Hey. I would like that book
on nuclear physics, please.
Sir, I have no idea
what kind of investigation he is doing.
He's either out buying books
or at the library.
PAKISTAN ARMY WILL BE
A GREAT POWER BY 1980
Dr. Faisal, Arif, Azam.
Azam... Where have I seen that name before?
Yes!
It's just research and analysis.
Forget about seeing any action.
He was angry when he came,
but I don't know what's going on now.
Damn it.
Nasreen! Are you okay?
Had I known
there'd be so many toilet trips,
I would never have gotten pregnant.
- Can I help?
- What would you do?
Nobody can help, but I need to sit down.
Now I know why they have
western toilets abroad.
Pakistani scientists
are educated and intelligent.
They are here from abroad.
- What are you doing?
- What would I do without you?
Come on. I have to rush to the bathroom.
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
- Do you have western toilets?
- Western toilets?
You seem to enjoy luxuries, mister.
Squat toilets work better though.
Hey, do you have western toilets here?
BILLA'S SANITARY WARE SHOP
No, you won't get it anywhere.
It has to be ordered specially.
- Okay.
- It's quite a process to get it.
Though I did get it done
on government orders a few years back.
I had a tough time.
I need it urgently.
My mom struggles to use squat toilets.
- May Almighty help her.
- Yeah.
- It'll be quite expensive.
- I have the advance payment right here.
- All right. It's 500 rupees.
- Okay.
- And 100 rupees for the labor...
- Here you go.
Consider it done.
- Listen.
- Yeah?
Well, I'm spending so much...
If I could see the job you did before,
I would feel a lot better.
- Yes, of course.
- Okay.
- Where is it?
- The address should be here.
Where is Shahi Street?
Here it is. There it is.
In all of Rawalpindi,
only Billa can get this done.
Fantastic! Thank you.
House of the People,
elections results are out
and, by winning 298 seats,
the Janata Party has defeated
Madam's government with a full majority.
This defeat is attributed to the emergency
declared by the prime minister.
This is the worst result
the current government has ever faced.
As per our sources...
You lost the Raebareli seat, Madam.
Good.
Now I'll have the time
to read some good books.
Who is being elected
as the next PM by the alliance?
This is Mahatma Gandhi's nation.
Government can never be
bigger than the constitution.
The abuse faced by the citizens
during the emergency
will be compensated.
That sounds like revenge to me, Mr. PM.
To me, it sounds like justice.
Will we see a change
in Pakistan policy, Mr. PM?
Anything can be resolved through talks.
They are our closest neighbors.
They should be our closest friend too.
Don't you think
that will be difficult, Mr. PM?
You are very difficult
to convince, my friend.
All good things are difficult to achieve.
But my government...
will not stop trying.
But, sir...
End this investigation.
It's a waste of time and money.
Thanks to the conspiracy theories
you and your Madam came up with,
our relationships
with neighboring countries are ruined.
I beg to differ, sir.
Because of our intel,
even Israeli's Mossad
is looking for
Pakistan's nuclear facility.
Sir, I don't think you realize
how dangerous this situation is.
Pakistan has made a deal with Gadhafi.
They'll provide nuclear bombs
in exchange for funding.
And soon, every Islamic dictator
and terrorist group will have this bomb!
Sir, this could start World War III.
That's why Israel wants to stop Pakistan.
And Pakistan is a direct threat to us.
We have to continue
this mission on a war footing, sir.
Mr. Kao,
these issues can only be resolved
through peace talks and diplomacy.
Violence won't change anything.
End this mission.
Okay, sir.
Then you should post diplomats
on the borders too.
Why do we need an army?
50% budget cut.
Then we'll have to stop
half our operations.
Our new PM thinks we are spies
for the opposition party.
What were you expecting?
So, what did you say?
I resigned.
Sir?
This is the only way
to divert PM's attention from RAW.
Continue the operation in Pakistan.
Away from PM's eyes.
This is my last order.
Yes, sir.
Stop.
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
- Is Shahi Street this way?
- Yes. Who are you?
- Plumber.
- I see.
Madam called me.
Madam called you?
Hey, where are you going?
Madam, are your neighbors not here?
They left seven months back.
- Okay.
- Did they not pay your dues?
- Actually...
- Come here.
Okay.
Thank you, madam.
Weren't some foreigners living here?
No, the husband was a Pathan.
I see.
But his wife was a foreigner.
Okay.
What was his name, madam?
I don't know,
but they called him Mr. Khan.
I see.
Would you like some tea, son?
Sure, I would love some.
Thank you.
Yes, madam.
Those people...
They never talked to anyone
or made friends with anyone.
I see.
- I even invited them over for tea one day.
- Really?
She just made a face and left.
Madam, what did he do for a living?
Well, I don't know,
but a government vehicle
came to pick him up every morning.
Along with a military guard.
And that woman
would come outside in just a slip,
and go, "Bye-bye."
She'd come to see him off.
Good heavens.
How did he look, madam?
How did he look?
Well, like all our Pathans.
Big and tall.
Didn't they have any kids?
Yes, they had two daughters.
They were around the same age as Gullu.
And they used to play together sometimes.
Hi, Gullu. Come here.
Which school do you attend?
Who are you?
Peace be upon you.
Your foreign neighbors
left without paying my dues.
- Well, that's how they are.
- Yeah.
They were the ones
who looted India and Pakistan.
Yes. We won't spare them.
They caused the partition.
They divided us...
- Peace be upon you.
- Tariq!
Nasreen's dad came by.
He took her to the hospital.
Hospital?
- What happened, Nasreen?
- It's nothing.
I just felt dizzy.
- Don't worry.
- How can we not?
Thank God I came by.
What if something happened to you?
Dad, please don't start again.
Well, where were you?
You weren't at the shop.
Tariq is really busy with work.
Please don't make a scene.
- What else does he do?
- Dad, please leave.
I'll go home with him.
May God protect you.
Come on.
- Hey.
- Come on.
Very good, Gullu.
Do you know about their dad's work?
Okay, Gullu, what were their names?
Sabah and Sara.
Sabah was nice
but Sara always fought with me.
Really?
Which school did they attend?
That English school. Mary something.
Very good.
Form a line. One by one. Don't run.
Hey! Where are you off to, mister?
Who do you want to meet?
Forget me. Meet Jinnah.
Come on. Take it.
Here are the admission records.
I don't know,
but they called him Mr. Khan.
Here's some tea, sir.
Sir, A.Q. Khan is the scientist
who is here from abroad.
The facility must be in here.
Man, I ask for a chicken
and you hand me an egg.
Sir, this name
is critical for the mission.
I need some more resources...
I won't waste my resources on the basis
of the toilet they use to take a dump.
Finer details
make the bigger picture, sir!
Kao always taught us that...
He's gone, son.
Your boss has abandoned you.
Now, you're under my control.
You can hate me all you like.
But imagine if I turn out to be right.
How can you be right?
You're your father's son after all.
And your child will be born
with the same dirty blood.
"Blessed be the sacred land,
happy be the bounteous realm."
Teach him that.
Your mission is over.
- Sir...
- You are dismissed.
Sir!
I always knew you were up to something.
Your behavior was always off.
Who knows what else you are hiding.
Tell me! How long has this been going on?
- Tell me.
- It's not what you think.
Damn it...
Who were you talking to?
Speak, you asshole.
Who is your mistress?
I've even seen you
with your son at the playground.
I won't let you
live with my daughter. Never!
I'll tell her everything. Everything!
There's a problem, sir.
His father-in-law heard his conversation.
Cover's blown. Means he's a goner.
Sir?
Finish Tariq.
Tariq.
Tariq, someone is at the door.
Wait here. I'll get that.
In theory, Pakistan is a democracy.
But in reality,
the military runs the country.
The PM's chair could be toppled.
General Zia-ul-Haq
was a very cunning and radical dictator.
Things were going
to get tougher for India.
This location is surrounded by these hills
and drilling is going on here.
Once we have the exact depth
and integrity of the tunnel,
we'll transfer the device
from the nuclear facility.
It'll be a swift operation, sir.
Mr. Khan, you have made Pakistan proud.
Please relax for a while.
It's not easy to get an appointment
for a drink with you.
- Cheers.
Shoot!
General Zia-ul-Haq. Put your guns down!
Sir.
Mr. Prime Minister, you're under arrest
for corruption and money embezzlement.
Pakistan won't be governed
by corrupt politicians,
but by the Pakistani Army.
O Ever-living and Sustainer,
with your mercy, we appeal.
I bear witness
that there is no deity but Allah
And Muhammed is the Messenger of Allah.
If anyone wants to pay their respects...
I bear witness that there
is no god except the One God.
They were thieves.
They shot him and took off.
This city is going to the dogs.
My brother-in-law...
Tariq, let me explain. Listen...
He didn't know anything.
You don't think before you act.
"Cover's blown. Means he's a goner."
Didn't Sharma say this?
For the first time,
Aslam defied his orders.
He saved your life.
Who are you?
I've been living
in Pakistan for nine years.
Senior Field Officer Raman Singh.
I know Aslam.
And now I get to meet you officially.
Agent? You are both Sharma's pets!
Calm down, Tariq!
Don't interfere with my work.
I won't stop till I finish this mission.
You can tell Sharma that.
A.Q. Khan! I was watching him too.
I submitted a report four years ago.
No one bothered to read it.
We can work together.
We are running out of time.
- Are the maps in order?
- Yes, sir.
- Evening, everyone.
- Evening, sir.
What's the news from the Jews?
Sir, according to Mossad,
the nuclear facility is in Quetta.
Source of intel?
Issac. He's our contact in Tel Aviv.
He said there's a lot
of military movement in Quetta.
The Israelis are planning
an aerial attack on Quetta.
- When?
- No confirmation yet.
And he has shared some aerial photos, sir.
Sir, Mossad's information is never wrong.
How about yours?
Ladies and gentlemen!
Martial law has been declared in Pakistan.
General Zia-ul-Haq will now lead
Pakistan from Islamabad.
After her dad's demise,
she has forgotten to smile.
He was both her mom and dad.
We have to clean all the crockery at home.
Nasreen is very quiet at home too.
Can she stay here for a few days?
It might cheer her up.
Yeah, I think that's better.
This is her maternal home.
Sorry, Uncle. I couldn't come to work
for the last few days.
Don't worry about work.
We're going through a rough patch.
What do you mean?
What happened?
I lost an order of 400 new uniforms.
Four hundred?
It was the biggest order this year.
It was a uniform with a new design.
That rascal Hamid got the order instead.
Come on. Food is served.
As God wills.
Tariq!
Why are you avoiding me?
I'm not, Nasreen.
Then what is it?
I need you the most right now.
And you are pushing me away.
For the last few days,
you have been distracted.
Please tell me what's bothering you.
I don't have an answer for you.
I'm not with you just for the good times.
Don't you trust me?
Prime Minister's office.
Excuse me, sir.
There's a scheduled call from Pakistan.
- General Zia-ul-Haq is on the line.
- Thank you.
General Zia.
Mr. PM, how are you?
Good. How are you?
All is well by God's grace.
- You must have received the news.
- Yes.
It was a corrupt administration, Mr. PM.
So I had to take this step.
I am sure you took this step
after thinking it through, General.
But I hope you'll restore
democracy in Pakistan soon.
I completely agree with you.
And I assure you,
we'll announce elections
within three months.
We must maintain
this transparency between our nations.
That's why I made
the first call to you, Mr. PM.
Our closest neighbor
should be our closest friend.
- It's most important for Pakistan.
- And also for India.
Thank you, Mr. PM.
God willing, we'll talk again soon.
Of course. Bye.
Bye.
- Who is next?
- China, sir.
Hamid!
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
I hear you got an order
for 1,000 uniforms.
No. That's just a rumor.
It's just for 400 jackets.
But wasn't the order for jackets
already fulfilled for this season?
It's a special order.
They are using a new material.
Anyway, as long as we get good business.
Tell me if you need
any help delivering it.
I'll get my scooter.
I don't have to worry about it.
The army will pick it up themselves.
Wow. We usually have to make
ten trips to the army camp.
But you're being treated like a VIP.
They are taking them
somewhere else, not the army camp.
Really?
Please tell me where
and I'll open a shop there.
Had I known, I would've opened
one myself, young man.
Before you did.
- May God protect you, Tariq.
- May God protect you.
Lord, free us from the cycle
of death but not from immortality.
Hail Lord Shiva.
Tariq, what's the plan?
An order of 400 army jackets
is leaving Rawalpindi tomorrow.
The army will make
the pickup themselves. This is a first.
Let's follow them.
I say let's kidnap them.
Shut up!
An innocent man died
because of your rash ways.
Nonsense.
Man, you are very ungrateful.
Anyone else would have fallen at my feet.
- I can't work with him.
- Tariq!
Okay, then let me fall at your feet.
- Let go...
- I'll touch your feet.
Cut out this drama!
Come here. Focus. Come on, Tariq.
Come on, Mr. Romeo. Come.
What?
Israel can launch
an air raid on Quetta anytime.
If we don't get the right location,
this mission will fail.
And if you turn out to be right,
then God save us.
We'll outmaneuver them.
We'll ask the army directly.
Really.
So what was wrong with my idea?
- Let's just kidnap them...
- Wait a minute!
Tariq, what are you thinking?
He must zip his lips.
And you...
Hail Lord Shiva.
- Sir!
- What's your name?
- Sohail Khan, sir.
Umar Sheikh, sir.
- Take their names down.
- Yes, sir.
What's wrong, sir? What did we do?
What are you carrying
in this truck? Liquor?
Liquor?
No, sir. It's a government order.
These are army jackets, sir.
Open it. Go and check.
Sir. We have strict orders.
We can't open this consignment, sir.
You follow rules but drive a vehicle
without a number plate?
It might have fallen off on the way, sir.
You're a disgrace to Pakistani Army.
I'll make it sure
you two are court-martialed!
- Court-martialed.
- Sir.
Sorry, sir. You can check the consignment.
Let's go.
Move aside! Sir.
Only jackets, sir.
Where to?
Sorry, sir, but we can't reveal it.
Kahuta, sir. We're taking these to Kahuta.
Sir, we're running late for the briefing.
- But how dare they talk to their senior...
- Sir, briefing.
Fix the number plate! Scoundrels!
- Sir.
- Sir!
Get lost!
Kahuta. It's a small town.
It's just an hour and a half
from Rawalpindi.
A.Q. Khan could commute
easily to that location.
But I wonder.
Why would Pakistan build the facility
so close to the Indian border?
Hidden in plain sight.
Ever heard this idiom?
I'm suffocating in this uniform.
Take this.
I must admit, though,
you did look like a major.
How long would it take
to grow your beard back?
It was years of hard work.
Wait a minute.
Didn't you officiate Mr. Romeo's wedding?
If the maulvi is fake,
can the wedding be real?
When the couple agrees,
who cares about the maulvi?
- Hail Lord Shiva!
- Nasreen, you...
- Why?
Did you think you could get rid of me?
Food is ready. Freshen up and come in.
Can you forgive me?
The problem
is that I can't stay angry with you.
I couldn't help your dad.
We can't do anything
to change what God has willed.
And the same God has blessed us
with this bundle of joy.
- What happened?
- Give me your hand.
Come on. Sit down. Easy.
Sit down.
- It's...
- Have you thought of a name?
Yeah, I do have a name in mind.
I'll tell you one day.
Have you ever thought
about moving away to live a peaceful life?
I'm always at peace when I'm by your side.
But honestly, tell me.
I can live in hell if you are with me.
Nasreen.
Let's go. I think the baby is hungry.
You are right, Mr. PM.
Pakistani sweets can't compete with this.
Thank you for sending
these gifts from India.
You are most welcome, General.
By the way, how is your health now?
Well, my knees are killing me.
You should try yoga.
You'll see the difference.
Intriguing I must say, Mr. PM.
I'll call you from home on Sunday
to discuss this in detail,
if you are free.
Sure. Look forward to it.
- May God protect you.
Be seated, please.
The PM is a close buddy of mine now.
Try some. It's delicious.
Please.
What were you saying
about the Kahuta facility, Sarfaraz?
Sir, we should deploy
anti-aircraft missiles there.
Sir, with increased movement,
the enemies might spot us.
India can't imagine that we're building
the bomb right under their nose.
He's right.
If we must, gun down
a few Indians in Kashmir first.
That will keep them distracted.
- Peace be upon you.
- Peace be upon you too.
- Tea, please.
- Sure. Have a seat.
There are many soldiers here.
I counted around 70.
Do you know
of any job openings in this area?
Maybe some factories looking for workers?
No, my friend.
The shops you see here,
the vegetable vendor,
the snacks shop, the barber shop,
they opened in the last few years
when they built the army camp
on the other side of the hills.
Really? How big is the camp?
I've never seen it.
They don't allow civilians there.
I wonder what they do there.
It stinks all night.
Stinks? What could they be making there?
- We want two teas.
- Peace be upon you.
Why don't you ask them directly?
If we don't return
in an hour, inform Control.
Aslam, if you have
a gun with you, leave it here.
I didn't bring a gun here. I'm not a fool.
Let's go.
Look. You're taking a huge risk.
This is the only way
to convince your Sharma.
He's not my Sharma. Nonsense.
- Come on. Watch your step.
- What have I gotten myself into?
Tariq, let's go back, man.
Up there?
Keep an eye out. I'll be back.
Hey!
Hands up!
Please don't shoot, sir!
- Please don't.
- What were you doing?
- We lost our way.
- What way?
- Our...
- Speak up!
- The way to our village, sir.
- Yes, sir.
- Which village?
- You know, the one... Baral.
- Baral.
- Yes.
Turn around.
- Can I put my hands down?
- Shut up!
- Not there.
- Don't be smart with me.
Move.
- What's going on, sir?
- Be quiet.
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah.
There it is! We found Kalu.
- Kalu?
- Our Kalu. Here's our Kalu.
- Here's our Kalu.
- Kalu! Yes!
This idiot was missing since morning, sir.
- We were out looking for him.
- Go on, then.
Where were you? Did you get anything?
- We did.
- Here.
We found Kalu.
Don't you guys understand orders?
I didn't expect this from you.
I'm sorry, Mr. Sharma.
But if A.Q. Khan
was staying in Rawalpindi,
why would they make
a research facility in Quetta?
- Tariq's theory makes sense.
- It's nonsense.
Sir, this is Tariq.
- Hey.
- I know I'm called the son of a traitor.
But if you don't stand with us today,
your son will be called son of a fool.
What do you mean?
History won't remember us agents.
But your name will be on the board.
"Officer Sharma,
whose lack of vision made us sit idly
as the country was destroyed."
Think about it, sir.
If they raid the wrong location,
our mission will be exposed.
It'll be impossible to stop Pakistan
from testing a nuclear bomb.
A nuclear bomb in an unstable country
like Pakistan means destruction for India.
Decide with your head, sir, not emotions.
- Hello.
- Raman Singh, you're a senior agent.
And you know very well
that without solid physical evidence,
we can't stop Israel.
Yes.
If Israel attacked Quetta
and it's not the right location,
Pakistan won't spare another minute.
Before we attack Kahuta,
they will conduct the nuclear test.
Then they'll aim their guns at Delhi.
Yeah.
Israel will carry out
the air strike in the next 48 hours.
I will wait for physical evidence.
Sharma has agreed to stay by the phone
for the next 48 hours.
And he'll wait for our report.
Israel won't back off
without physical evidence.
If your theory is proven wrong,
you'll have to go back to India.
Alone.
I'll go into the facility.
Have you lost it? It's a suicide mission.
You don't have to atone for your father.
Don't make a big mistake
trying to pay penance.
We don't keep score with our mothers.
So why would we with our country?
A country is what its people are.
After Dad's demise,
many called me the son of a traitor.
They kicked us out of our house.
No one helped my dying mother.
Hate...
I just hated them.
But how can I forget the sardar
who never let me
sleep hungry at the gurudwara?
Or Father Joseph, who fought everyone
to admit me in school?
And Mr. Kao, who trained me
to make me capable
of protecting this country?
We are India.
We don't feed on hatred, but on love.
We won our freedom with love and peace.
Tell me. Is there another country like us?
I can do anything
to protect a country like that, Raman.
Anything.
My friend,
go across the hills.
We have your back.
My gun will take care of the soldiers.
We live under your skies
Nestled in your lap
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
- The plan isn't foolproof.
- We don't have time.
MY DEAR NASREEN
We stayed up for you all our lives
Now you must come to put us to sleep
May your head be held high forever
O Motherland
Even if nobody knows us
GOODBYE NASREEN
AMAN
Even if nobody knows us
We flow anonymously in the wind
Like fragrance...
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
What's wrong, Nasreen?
The baby has not moved since yesterday.
Everything is fine, Nasreen.
It happens. You are fine.
Please wait outside.
I'll run the rest of the tests.
Okay.
- Is everything all right?
- Yes.
- Wear this.
- Why do I have to wear this?
They won't let you enter without it.
- Why are you forcing me?
- It's an X-ray machine.
The radiation it emits is so strong
it will remain in your body.
It can turn you impotent.
Its light is so dangerous
that we don't touch the machine
without this jacket on.
It's dangerous.
Please take Nasreen home.
I'll be back soon.
- But Tariq...
- Just...
- We don't need to enter the facility.
- Why?
Because Kahuta only has one barber shop.
I can't believe it, man.
You're a genius.
Remember, this is the signal.
What is this?
Mr. Romeo's signals are also odd like him.
Please come in.
Peace be upon you, sir.
- Please come.
- Sir.
- I want a shave.
Hey, son, order some tea.
Please come, sir.
Sir, the chair is free now.
- Well, give me a haircut.
- Please come.
When will he give the signal?
Chotu!
- Yes, sir?
- Clean this up.
Okay.
You...
Oh, my God. A fight broke out. Look!
- How dare you tease my sister?
- What's going on?
- How dare you...
- He's hitting him.
- My sister...
- Get off me!
What's the matter?
Stop them!
- Somebody stop them!
- Stop!
Let go!
Get off me!
Don't interfere!
This is my hair. I'm taking it.
But look at the mess here!
Clean it up, Chotu!
You took long enough.
Hey! Don't mess with me!
I won't spare you. You scoundrel.
Hey!
Hey, idiot!
I won't spare you!
What next, Tariq?
We need to take it to India.
Lahore?
Man...
They have tight security here.
How will you board Samjhauta Express
without your passport and visa?
No other way to reach India sooner.
Wagah is just 20 minutes out.
You'll get caught if you board.
Bhanu Chak village
is between Wagah and Attari.
Wait for me at that railway crossing.
Are you crazy?
See you later.
Go to that line.
- The papers aren't in order.
- They are.
- No, they aren't.
- Sir, it's all there.
Passport, please.
Lift your arms.
Hey, don't touch my turban.
Okay, all right. Go on.
Hey. Please forgive me.
- Step aside.
- Sir.
I said step aside!
- What's the matter, sir?
- Step aside.
- Go on.
- Sir.
Go on.
Sir! Please check this also. What's wrong?
You don't have a turban
in your passport photo.
- Be assured, everything else is there.
- Really?
Take it off.
- What?
- Take your turban off!
Take the turban off?
- They want to remove our turbans.
- He's asking us to remove them.
Take off our turbans?
He's asking us to take off our turbans.
He's asking us to remove our turbans.
It's our pride!
Don't forget.
This is also the land of our gurus.
When I can fight against 1,25 lakhs,
only then will I be called a Sikh.
One who says this is free of miseries.
God is truth.
This train won't leave without my turban.
- Wait a minute.
- Sir.
Do you want to start a war
on the platform?
- Sir, you can go.
- Okay.
Come on, friends. Let's go to Amritsar.
Come on!
The Sikhs of the Lord are victorious!
Come on, friends!
Here, son.
- Is this suitcase yours?
- Yes, sir.
- Whose bag is this?
- It's mine, sir.
- Whose is this? Is this yours?
- Yes, it's mine.
Oh, my god!
Where is it?
- What, sir?
- My wedding ring.
- Wedding ring?
- My wedding ring is missing.
Where's my wedding ring? Find it.
Was it expensive?
It wasn't expensive,
but my wife will kill me.
She will kick me out of the house.
- Faisal, listen carefully.
- Yes, sir.
Coach number seven, seat number seven.
He's a sardar. Arrest him.
- Arrest the sardar in seat number seven.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, my God.
I've been married for just two years.
Yes, sir. We're looking for him, sir.
She will kick me out of the house. Stop.
- Speak.
- Why is it like this, sir?
Nothing. Nothing.
Hey!
Get back inside!
Go up!
Are you okay?
- Yes. Lahore's asset. Quick! Let's go.
- Come on.
Not meds, just prayers.
Sir, coach number seven, seat number 19.
A woman in a blue dress,
wheatish complexion.
There's a package in her suitcase.
Send it to the lab.
What is in it?
Hair samples of people
working in the Kahuta facility.
If they are making a bomb,
they are exposed to radiation every day.
So the radiation levels
must be high in their hair samples.
You have only 12 hours, sir.
Please don't waste any time.
Amandeep Ajitpal Singh, signing off.
Sodhi, listen carefully.
Wait a minute, please.
Special Agent Sandeep Singh.
We have to check your bag.
- Check her bag.
- Give it.
What's the matter, sir? My bag...
- Are the samples here?
- They will be soon.
The technician should be here early.
Give it to me!
What is it?
Check for radioactivity.
How long will it take?
Hurry up.
Radiation markers are very high.
And there are fragments
of highly enriched uranium too.
Only one thing can be made
with this kind of uranium.
Atom bomb.
- Sharma?
- The facility is in Kahuta, not in Quetta.
We have physical evidence.
- Please stop Israel.
- Shit!
Fifty kilometers from the target.
Come on, Issac.
Issac, Santosh here.
Lock in the target.
T minus 10.
Issac, Mossad.
Get me the air marshal now! Go!
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Abort the mission.
It is not in Quetta.
Four.
Three.
This is the air marshal.
Squadron leader, abort the mission.
Two.
Abort the mission immediately.
Sir, the nuclear facility is close.
The location is Kahuta.
We must take action, sir.
You carried out this mission
without my permission.
We'll discuss that later.
Our agents wouldn't have risked
their lives in the field if we had time.
I said I'll think about it.
We need to bomb the Kahuta facility, sir.
I can't push our country into another war
without thinking it through.
Our agents did a fantastic job.
They made the country proud.
We are indebted to them for their service.
Sir?
It was stopped in time, my friend.
- Okay, sir.
- Wait a minute.
I'm sorry for my behavior.
Sitting at this end of the phone,
I considered myself
to be the biggest patriot.
Shouting orders. Swearing.
Calling someone a traitor,
pointing fingers
and that made me a patriot.
But thanks to you, I know from now on.
Patriotism is not in the blood
but in your soul.
Anyone can talk,
but those who put it into action...
I salute them.
I don't know about history,
but my children will know
who Amandeep Singh was.
Son of the nation.
A true soldier.
No one can take your country from you.
Connect me to General Zia.
Mr. PM, please listen to me.
Give me a straight answer.
Is Pakistan making
a nuclear weapon or not?
I don't owe you an explanation, Mr. PM.
I'm not obliged.
But you are a friend.
That's why I'm telling you.
Pakistan is not making a nuclear bomb.
Then what's going on in Kahuta?
I don't know
what you are talking about, Mr. PM.
Don't pretend, General.
We have physical evidence
from the Kahuta nuclear facility.
I was wrong.
Pakistan can't be trusted.
I hope you remember
that you surrendered in every war.
We won't go easy on you this time.
Shut down your nuclear facility now!
Mr. PM...
Faisal!
Shut down the nuclear facility.
Sir? We are very close to our goal.
If we stop the work now,
it'll set us back years.
General, we'll soon test it...
Can we test it in the next 15 minutes?
We need some more time, General, and...
India's fighter jets
can reach Pakistan within 15 minutes.
They'll turn
our 500-million-dollar facility to dust!
We'll be left picking up pieces.
Shut the facility right now!
Yes, sir.
I'll issue the orders
to shut down the facility.
How did the Indians find out about Kahuta?
Only RAW could have done this.
A handful of Indian spies
exposed us in front of the world.
Pakistan Army, ISI,
police.
Just a handful of their spies
have exposed us to the world.
Pakistan's dream
has been destroyed, General.
Are we gonna take this lying down?
Tariq, where have you been?
- Tariq.
- I'm back.
I won't go anywhere now.
What happened?
Is everything all right?
I have some good news, Nasreen.
We are leaving for Dubai
this Friday night.
Dubai?
Yes, I found a job there.
- Really? In Dubai?
- Yes.
Thank God.
Nasreen, I've never said...
this enough to you.
I love you a lot, Nasreen.
Tell me something I don't know.
There are RAW agents in Pakistan.
Impossible, sir.
- Really?
- It's not possible.
It's possible!
Bastards!
They know about Kahuta.
RAW agents are working here
while ISI is twiddling their thumbs.
Find them and finish them.
Yes.
Or I'll have you skinned in public!
I'll give you 24 hours.
Twenty-four.
I have a bunch of morons
with me in Pakistan!
Morons!
Get me the records
of every call made to India
in the last two weeks.
You have 12 hours.
- Tickets for Dubai.
- Tickets for Dubai?
Easy. Go easy.
A total of 7,255 calls were made.
Mark the calls made
between 10:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m.,
especially from offices and shops.
- Okay, sir.
- One more thing.
Concentrate on calls made to Delhi.
- How many people?
- Twenty-one.
Shut down the phone lines.
Start the raids.
If anyone tells you they are orphans,
assume they are RAW agents.
Finish them on the spot.
But, sir, some of them
might be Pakistani citizens.
There are martyrs in every war.
Operators, listen carefully.
We have orders to ban all calls.
- Do not patch through any calls.
- Yes, sir.
You are going to a new place,
so far away from all of us.
How will you take care of yourself?
Tariq is with me.
Don't worry.
I'll send flight tickets for you too.
We'll miss your biryani after all.
- Won't you invite me to Dubai?
- Can you make biryani?
- Well, I'll learn to.
- Then I'll invite you too.
I wish you all the success.
And may God fulfil all your wishes.
Amen.
My child.
- It's time for Dubai.
- Yeah.
These kids will go to Dubai,
and we'll still be here stitching clothes.
Don't make a fuss without a reason
Yes, sir?
- You're shutting shop early today.
- Yeah, I have some snacks left.
I can pack them for you.
- Do you live here?
- Yeah, I have a bed here.
Do your parents live with you?
Yeah. Want to meet them?
Mom!
Dad, come outside, please!
Nasreen, I forgot
to say goodbye to some friends.
- I'll go see them.
- Come back soon.
Yeah.
Victory to thee, O Hanuman!
Ocean of wisdom.
You're the divine messenger of Lord Rama...
You dispel the darkness...
Dad!
No uniform on the body
And no stars on the shoulder
We live under your skies
Our flag will not fly low
Whenever there's a mention of sacrifice
We will be first in the queue
No matter if we're on the earth or not
We will be smiling among stars
Tariq!
Tariq, better take off from here.
What about Aslam?
I came from his diner.
I could've saved him
if I'd gotten there in time.
Aslam?
Let's get out of here.
We can cross the border from Fazilka.
- Nasreen?
- Don't be crazy!
You have more chances if you escape alive.
For her sake, come with me!
Deceit leads to the same pain
whether it's India or Pakistan.
I won't let Nasreen and my baby
go through what I had to.
- I must go.
- I won't say goodbye.
I'll see you soon at our home,
in our country.
May Lord Shiva help you.
Why the hurry all of a sudden?
Flight time's changed.
I couldn't even say goodbye.
Drive carefully, man.
Are you okay?
If you weren't making
those calls to India, who was?
To India? I have no idea, sir.
Did you give the shop keys
to any employee?
Keys?
- Tariq?
Sir.
Inform the airport security.
Tariq Hussain and Nasreen.
If their IDs match, detain them.
Yes, sir!
Here's the airport, sir.
Lower it.
Come, Nasreen.
Good evening, sir. Passport, please.
There he is. Stop!
Thank you, sir. Have a safe flight.
Come.
Hands up!
Hail Lord Shiva.
Commandos, this way!
Look at this photo carefully.
Check-in area, waiting area,
just spread out.
Slow down, Tariq. I can't catch my breath.
We are at the security gate.
You guys check the left side.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Thank you.
- Come on.
- Please come forward.
- Have you seen him?
- Come on.
Show me the name entries.
- No, sir.
- No.
Have you seen him?
Yes, sir. He just went in.
Come on! Quick!
He has cleared immigration.
- Tariq...
- Just a few more steps.
You are holding my hand really tight.
Let go!
Something's off. What are you doing?
Sorry. Come on. Sit here.
Easy. Sit.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
But what's wrong with you?
It feels like we are running from someone.
What's wrong?
Tariq.
Tell me.
Come on. Tell me.
You are tired.
I'll get a wheelchair for you.
Come here. Sit on this.
Come.
Be careful.
We don't have adjoining
seats on the flight.
But don't worry.
You seem more worried than me.
I have been trying to tell you something.
Aman.
That's the name I have for our baby.
Do you like it?
Amazing.
It's a beautiful name.
Whether we have a boy or a girl,
it will work for both.
Aman.
There's some money in your bag.
Take care.
You're talking
as if you're going somewhere else.
There is a separate queue for women here.
A staff member will take you.
How about you?
I'll meet you on the other side.
My Lord knows
How I love you
Do you have the address?
Passport and ticket, ma'am.
Stop!
Long live India!
Come with me, quickly.
- What happened, sir?
- Nothing. Some security matter it seems.
Hey!
Ma'am, please mind your head.
Please have a seat.
Back off!
I said back off!
Surrender while you still can!
Shoot!
Sir, he's got our man.
Beloved
Forgive me
That I left you
In between, on the way
So as not to break the promise
I made to my mother
I broke the promise I made to you
Go, Nasreen.
Go.
It is you who is the one
But what can we do
We call India our life
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
May God protect you, Nasreen.
Welcome to Dubai International Airport.
Tariq?
My name is Kao. I'm Tariq's friend.
Where is Tariq?
"My dear Nasreen,
if Mr. Kao is reading this letter to you,
then I'm not in this world anymore."
Nasreen, you always said
that I keep secrets.
I am guilty of that.
I've always loved you with all my heart.
But bound by my duty,
I had to keep some secrets from you.
Today, I want to tell you everything.
My name is Amandeep Singh,
and I'm an Indian.
Because of the sacrifice of Indian agents,
the secret nuclear facility in Kahuta
was exposed to the world.
Yet, Zia kept denying this truth.
Why should Pakistan
indulge in the proliferation
against which Pakistan,
on principles, is opposed to?
Because we have no intentions
of developing a nuclear device.
Sir, we are honorable people.
But the truth can't be kept under wraps.
In 2004, A.Q. Khan admitted
that Pakistan had sold nuclear technology
to rogue nations
like North Korea and Iran.
We should... I would be worried
more about what you say about me.
Not what Bush says or Dick Cheney says.
I... don't care.
Pakistan couldn't conduct
nuclear tests for the next 20 years.
In 1998...
under the leadership
of PM Mr. Atal Bihari Vajpayee,
India conducted its second nuclear test.
And it became the biggest nuclear power
of the subcontinent.
It's not the wind
that holds our tricolor high.
It's the last breath of our martyrs.
We live under your skies
Nestled in your lap
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
We stayed up for you all our lives
Now you must come to put us to sleep
May your head be held high forever
O Motherland
Even if nobody knows us
We stayed up for you all our lives
Now you must come to put us to sleep
May your head be held high forever
O Motherland
Even if nobody knows us
We flow anonymously in the wind
Like fragrance...
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
No uniform on the body
And no stars on the shoulder
Our flag will not fly low
Whenever there's a mention of sacrifice
We will be first in the queue
No matter if we're on the earth or not
We will be smiling among stars
Let the garden that we call India
Keep flowering
We are the only one in the world who
Call our soil "Mother"
Subtitle translation by:
Sheela Sijin Mathews